Finding Aid to the Women's Project Theater records SSC.MS.00361
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. Administrative Files, 1972-2010; 29.042 linear feet (34 containers)
  - Rehearsed Readings - listings, 1990-1991 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings -correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings - listings, 1992-1993 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings - programs, 1993-1994 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings - programs, 1994-1995 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings, 1995-1996 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings -series info., 1995-1996 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings, 1997 (Box 75)
  - Rehearsed Readings - cast lists, 1997-1998 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - Publicity, 1998 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - Publicity, 1999 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - Publicity, 2000 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - Publicity, 2001 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - Publicity, 2002 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - Publicity, 2003 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - Publicity, 2004 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings - miscellaneous readings, 2004 (Box 76)
  - Rehearsed Readings (Box 76)
  - Report on WP Theater by Pamela Wagner, 1978-1979 (Box 85)
  - Reports, Minority Reports, 1994 (Box 85)
  - Reports, Play Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 85)
  - Jeffrey Richards - press releases ('Signs of Life', 'Letters Home'), 1985-1986 (Box 76)
  - Jeffrey Richards - Julia Miles interview, 1978-1979 (Box 76)
  - Scripts, 1993-1994 (Box 76)
  - Script Logs - "A", 1979-1997 (Box 76)
  - Script Logs - "B", 1978-1997 (Box 76)
  - Script Logs - "C", 1979-1997 (Box 76, Box 77)
  - Script Logs - "D", 1986-1997 (Box 77)
  - Script Logs - "E", 1987-1996 (Box 77)
  - Script Logs - "F", 1978-1996 (Box 77)
  - Script, uproduced - "Funny, You Don't Look Like a Grandma", 1992-1993 (Box 77)
  - Script Logs - "G", 1972-1996 (Box 77)
  - Script Logs - "H", 1978-1997 (Box 77, Box 78)
  - Script Logs - "I", 1978-1996 (Box 78)
  - Script Logs - "J", 1987-1997 (Box 78)
  - Script Logs - "K", 1987-1996 (Box 78)
  - Script Logs -"L", 1978-1998 (Box 78)
  - Script Logs - "M", 1978-1997 (Box 78)
  - Script Logs - "N", 1978-1997 (Box 79)
  - Script Logs - "O", 1978-1996 (Box 79)
  - Script Logs - "P", 1977-1997 (Box 79)
  - Script Logs -"Q", 1978-1997 (Box 79)
  - Script Logs - "R", 1978-1995 (Box 79)
  - Script Logs - "S", 1974-1997 (Box 79, Box 80)
  - Script Logs - "T", 1978-1997 (Box 80)
  - Script Logs - "U", 1984-1993 (Box 80)
  - Script Logs -"V", 1978-1997 (Box 80)
  - Script Logs - "W", 1978-1997 (Box 80)
  - Script Logs - "Y", 1978-1997 (Box 80)
  - Script Logs - "Z", 1979-1990 (Box 80)
  - Script Log - Mail Log, 1987 (Box 80)
  - Script Log - Past Productions - "D", 1981-1992 (Box 80)
  - Script Log - Production - Reading possibility lists, 1990-1993 (Box 80)
  - Script sign-in and sign-out book, 1989-1995 (Box 80)
  - Script log-in sheets, 1996-1997 (Box 80)
  - Script - unproduced -"The Clearing House", 1991 (Box 80)
  - Script - unproduced - Margaret Sanger Project, 1992 (Box 80)
  - Script - unproduced - "Relative Strangers", 1994 (Box 80)
  - Script - unproduced - "Remembrance", 2007 (Box 80)
  - Season Playbills, 1987-2003 (Box 80)
  - Season Playbills, 1988-1997 (Box 80)
  - Singular Sensations - Festival, 1993-1994 (Box 80)
  - Singular Sensations - Festival, 1994-1995 (Box 81)
  - Skirting the Issues - Cabaret, 1992-1993 (Box 81)
  - Skirting the Issues - Cabaret, 1992-1993 (Box 81)
  - Skirting the Issues - Cabaret - publicity, 1992-1993 (Box 81)
  - Skirting the Issues - Cabaret - script, 1993 (Box 81)
  - Sound recordings of Skirting the Issues, 1992-1993; 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 95)
  - "Snicker Factor: An Evening of Political Satire", 1986-1987 (Box 81)
  - Sound recordings of Snicker Factor, 1986; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 95)
  - Southern Exposure series - Misc., 1990-1991 (Box 81)
  - Southern Exposure series - Misc., 1990-1991 (Box 81)
  - Southern Exposure series - contacts, contracts, 1990-1991 (Box 81)
  - Southern Exposure series - "Today", 1990-1992 (Box 81)
  - Southern Exposure series - "Bear Facts", 1991-1992 (Box 81)
  - Southern Exposure series - "Chain/Late Bus to Mecca", 1992 (Box 81)
  - Staff and Member Artist lists, 1996-2003 (Box 81)
  - Stationery (Box 81)
  - Stationery, 1978-1990 (Box 81)
  - Status of Women, 1990-1992 (Box 81)
  - Robert Sterling Clark Foundation, 1978-1991 (Box 81)
  - Subscription, 1994-2006 (Box 81)
  - Swedish Panel at CSC, 1991 (Box 81)
  - Sound recording of Symposium #1 and #2, 1988; 1 items (One audiocassette) (Box 96)
  - Sound recording of Symposium #3, Joyce West, 1988; 1 items (One audiocassette) (Box 96)
  - Take a Girl to the Women's Project, 1993-1995 (Box 81)
  - Take Your Daughter to Work, 1997 (Box 81)
  - Tandem Acts II, 1995 (Box 81)
  - Tandem Acts III, 1995-1996 (Box 81)
  - Tandem Acts IV, 1997 (Box 81)
  - Tandem Acts V - Barriers, Borders and Restraining Devices, 1998 (Box 81)
  - Tandem Acts VII, 1999 (Box 81)
  - Tandem Acts - VII, 2000 (Box 81)
  - Sound recordings of Tandem Acts, 1998; 4 items (4 audiocassettes) (Box 95)
  - Teachers Night on Broadway, 1995 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, General, 1990-2007 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Brochures, 1994-2001 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Budgets, 1990-1998 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Contests for Student Playwrights, 1992-1994 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Correspondence, 1991-1997 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Coursework, 1991-1992 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Curriculum, 1994 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Employees and Staff, 1991-1995 (Box 85)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Extended Day Program, 2008-2010 (Box 85, Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Feasibility Report, 1990 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Funding, 1992-1993 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Notes, 1991-1993 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Outreach, 1991-1992 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Pamphlet, 1997 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, 52nd Street Project, 1990 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, A&E, 1990-1993 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Aetna Foundation, 1987 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Alliance for the Acts, 1997 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Annenberg, 1996 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Arts Connection, 1992-1995 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Arts Partners, 1992 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Arts Vision, 1995 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Brooklyn Borough President, 1993 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Brooklyn Union Gas, 1992-1995 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, League of American Theatre Producers, 1994 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Lincoln Center, 1991-1992 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, National Endowment for the Arts, 1990 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, New York Foundation for the Arts (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, New York State Council for the Arts, 1991-1995 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Reader's Digest, 1991 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, St Xavier Church, 1993 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Townsend Harris, 1993 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, WNET-13, 1994 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Partners, Women's History Month, 1993 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Photographs, 1992-1995 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Playbills, 1996-2006 (Box 86)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Plays (Box 86, Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Proposals, 1992-1994 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Publicity, 1992-2000 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Readings, 2006 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Recognition, 2002 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Research, 1990-1997 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Scholarships, 2009 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, General, 1990-1996 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Bayard Rustic Educational Complex (BREC), 2008-2009 (Box 87)
  - Sound recording of Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights School Program at Bayard Rustic Educational Complex, Dropout Factory Cues, 1 items (One CD) (Box 97)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Bedford Stuyvesant, 1994-1996 (Box 87)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Bronx Regional High School, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Cascades High School, 2009-2010 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Concord High School, 2009-2010 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Conselyea Prep, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Murrow High School, 1991-1995 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Fannie Lou Hamer Freedom High School, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Fashion Industries, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Grace Dodge, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Independence High School, 2008-2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Jaqueline Kennedy Onassis High School, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, JFK Performing Arts, 1994 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Laguardia High School, 1993-1994 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Law and Public Service High School, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Liberty High School Academy for Newcomers, 2009-2010 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Lower East Side Preparatory High School, 2009-2010 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Martin Luther King Jr High School, 1995-1997 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Middle College High School, 1994 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Midtown Community, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Metropolitan High School, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Performing Arts Technical High School, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Restart Daytop, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Reynolds West Side High School, 2009-2010 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, St Lukes Cares Restart, 2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Two Bridges Academy, 1995 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Schools, Young Women's Leadership School, 2008-2009 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Student Notes, 1993 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Student Scripts, 1998-2005 (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Study Guide (Box 88)
  - Ten Centuries of Women Playwrights Education Program, Translation Grant, 1993 (Box 88)
  - Theatre Communications Group Inc., 1988-1991 (Box 81)
  - Theatre Communications Group Inc., 1989-1994 (Box 81)
  - Joan Thorne's project, 1987 (Box 81)
  - Ticket Statistics, 1983-1989 (Box 81)
  - Video recording of TV News Segment, WPP, 2001; 1 items (One VHS cassette tape) (Box 97)
  - Twentieth Anniversary, 1998 (Box 82)
  - Video recording of Twentieth Anniversary Highlights Mapping the Source of Power, 1998; 1 items (One VHS cassette tape) (Box 97)
  - Video recordings of Twenty Years and Counting, WPP master and copies, 1998; 1 items (One Beta-SP videocassette); 2 items (Two VHS cassette tapes) (Box 97)
  - Vietnamese Literature, 1995-1997 (Box 82)
  - Vietnamese Scripts, 1997 (Box 82)
  - Winter Benefit, 1999 (Box 82)
  - Women and Song - cabaret - program, misc., 1979-1980 (Box 82)
  - Women and Song - cabaret benefits, 1995 (Box 82)
  - Women and Song - cabaret, 1995-1997 (Box 82)
  - Women and Song II - cabaret, 1996 (Box 82)
  - Video recording of Women and Song Benefit, 1995; 1 items (One VHS cassette tape) (Box 97)
  - Women Heroes - budgets, 1986 (Box 82)
  - Women Heroes - equity, personnel, 1985-1986 (Box 82)
  - Women Heroes: In Praise of Exceptional Women, 1986 (Box 82)
  - Women Heroes - misc., 1985-1986 (Box 82)
  - Women Heroes -programs, correspondence, press, 1986-1987 (Box 82)
  - Women Heroes - Series A, 1987 (Box 82)
  - Women Heroes - Series B, 1986 (Box 82)
  - Women Heroes TV project - fundraising, 1984-1987 (Box 82)
  - Sound recordings of Women Heroes, 1987; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 95)
  - Video recording of Women in Theatre with guests Julia Miles and Isobel Robins, 2002; 2 items (Two VHS cassette tape) (Box 97)
  - Sound recording of Women in Theatre Workshop November 7 and 8, 1997; 9 items (9 audiocassettes) (Box 96)
  - Women of Achievement Award, 1990 (Box 82)
  - Women of Achievement Award, 1987-2001 (Box 82)
  - Sound recording of WPP Women of Achievement Awards and Benefit with Laurie Anderson, Joan Osborne, Suzanne Vega, 2010; 1 items (One CD) (Box 97)
  - Sound recording of Jessica Tandy Acceptance Speech, 1987; 1 items (One audiocassette) (Box 96)
  - Women's Project Workshop, 1981-1982 (Box 82)
  - Women - The Emerging Force in Theatre - Apt./Dramatists, 1980 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now - Barnard - advertising, 1994 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now! - Barnard 1994 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now - Lifetime Filming, Barnard, production schedule, reservations, press, contact lists, 1994-1995 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now - festival, 1990-1999 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now - festival, 1993-1994 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now - festival, 1994 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now! - "In No Man's Land", 1994 (Box 82)
  - Women Write Now! -Playbill, 1994 (Box 82)
  - Words, Women, and Song - cabaret, 2004 (Box 82)
- SERIES III. Julia Miles papers, 1951-2007; 1.667 linear feet (2 containers)
  Series III of the WP Theater records consists primarily of the professional papers of Julia Miles, relating to her career as an actress and producer. Materials include photos, articles, correspondence, contracts, planners, press clippings, reviews, script pages, speeches, as well as papers pertaining to the League of Professional Theatre Women, the Women's Forum, and her production company, Four Women Productions. Papers are arranged alphabetically.
  - Acting Career, 1951-2004 (Box 83)
  - Acting Career - "The Jungle's Edge" - JM acting, 1960 (Box 83)
  - Acting Career - "Makepeace's Blackouts and Passages" - JM acting, 1961 (Box 83)
  - Acting Career - "Red Eye of Love" - JM acting, 1960-1961 (Box 83)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - Deal, 1978-1979 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - Legal, 1978-1987 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - Correspondence - Script Ideas, 1981-1999 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "Four Friends" budget, 1980 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "Four Friends" - Photos and production info., 1981 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "Four Friends" - reviews and press clippings, 1981-1982 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "Four Friends", 1979-1981 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "Four Friends" - script, 1980 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "The Living" - articles, story treatment, 1980 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "The Living" - correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box 83)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "The Living" - deal, 1981-1983 (Box 84)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "The Living" - production notes, 1982-1983 (Box 84)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "A Pair of Jacks", 1982-1983 (Box 84)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "Pretty Redwing", 1983-1989 (Box 84)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - screenplay returns, 1983-1984 (Box 84)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - "Sousa" contract, Filmway Pictures brochure, 1980 (Box 84)
  - Four Woman, Tolan/Miles Prod. - Steve Tesich press, 1978-1996 (Box 84)
  - Gina Wendkos/Frank Perry project, 1986 (Box 84)
  - League of Professional Theatre Women - newsletters, 1983-2007 (Box 84)
  - League of Professional Theatre Women - brochures, fliers, letters, 1998-2006 (Box 84)
  - Planners, 1999-2001 (Box 84)
  - JM Retirement, 1980-2003 (Box 84)
  - JM Speeches and notes handwritten, 1998-2000 (Box 84)
  - Women's Forum, Inc. - brochures, newsletters, 1994-2000 (Box 84)
  - Women's Forum, Inc. - contacts, newsletters, 1994-2003 (Box 84)